브로큰 플라워
(Broken Flowers, 2005)
돈 주앙을 만난 적 있소?
한 번도 없어요
- 그럼 왜 슬퍼하오?
- 없으니 슬프죠!
굉장해
[Man Chuckles] It's amazing. I had no
idea my own funeral could be so delightful.
내 장례식이 이리
즐거울 줄이야
It certainly brought your
career to a happy end. End?
이제 자넨
행복하게 은퇴하겠군
Leave off while they still
think of you as you were.
더 늙지 않고 이대로
기억될 테니까
All these wrinkles, these
lines, these gray hairs.
이 주름과 흰 머리를
좀 보게
[Don Juan] You'd spoil
any party, even a funeral.
이 장례식의 흥을
깨지 말아주게
No, no, no, my friend.
This is a great sight.
친구여, 이 어찌
멋지지 않은가!
Women and women and women.
이 여자들 좀 보게
The eternal hunger of women for love.
사랑에 굶주린 여인들로
가득하구나!
I pretty much have all my stuff.
짐은 다 싼 것 같아
Looks like you got a love letter
from one of your other girlfriends.
숨겨놓은 애인한테 온
편지인가 봐
I don't have any other
girlfriend, Sherry. Come on!
그런 거 없어, 쉐리
[Sighs] All right. I get it.
당신, 왜 이러는지 알아
No, you don't. But it's okay.
아니, 몰라
하지만 괜찮아
That's the way you are.
You're never going to change.
그게 당신이야
절대 바뀔 리 없어
I just don't think I
want to be with an...
한물간 돈 주앙과의
an over-the-hill
Don Juan anymore.
연애놀이는 이제 싫어
What do you want, Sherry?
원하는 게 뭐야?
What do you want, Don?
당신은?
I mean, I'm like your mistress,
난 당신 정부 같아
except you're not even married.
당신한텐 부인도 없는데
L
- Look at your friend Winston next door.
옆집 윈스턴을 봐
It looks like they're
having a great time.
정말 행복해 보여
Don't you ever want to have a family?
가정 가질 생각
해본 적 없어?
Well, is that what you want?
그런 걸 원해?
I don't know what I want, but I
just want to figure it out by myself.
나도 몰라
하지만 나 혼자
답을 찾겠어
By yourself.
혼자라...
Yeah.
그래
Maybe I'll call you sometime.
봐서 나중에 전화할게
Sherry?
쉐리!
##[TV: Continues]
[Woman] What are you but a
female? [Woman #2] Same as you!
- 별 것도 아닌 게
- 너도 마찬가지야
Nobody asked you. He never kissed
you. It was an impudent lie!
그와 키스도 못했잖아
어디서 거짓말을!
[Man] Yes, it was a lie. Don Juan told
me so himself. It was only publicity.
그거 거짓말이야
돈 주앙에게 직접 들었어
다들 알고 있다고!
[Man #2] He did not! Don't you...
그가 그럴 리 없어
네가 뭔데 부인 행세야?
[Woman] And who are you to give
orders here? [Woman #2] Who am I?
내가 누구냐고?
Don Juan said I was the girl whose kiss
he'd been seeking on a thousand women's lips!
그가 찾던 입술의 주인
그의 유일한 연인이지
I was the only one. He'd never
love anybody else in his life!
평생 나만 사랑했다 그랬어
[Woman #2] Ha! He loved you so much that
he went straight from you to another woman.
그럼 널 두고
왜 딴 여자한테 갔지?
He loved me! And loathed
young women like you.
- 내 남자였어!
- 딴 할멈들도 그리 말했지
Cat! Cow!
- 고양이 같은 년!
- 암소 같은 년!
Snake! Pig!
- 뱀 같은 년!
- 돼지 같은 년!
- 염소 같은 년!
- 족제비 같은 년!
Goat! Weasel!
- 벌레 같은 년!
- 아냐, 아냐, 아냐!
Worm! No, no, no, no!
[Crowd Laughing]
[Laughing Continues]
[Quiet Snoring]
[Phone Rings]
[Rings]
Yeah?
여보세요?
Hey, Winston.
아, 윈스턴
You at work?
직장이야?
It's Saturday. Of course. Yeah.
맞아, 오늘 토요일이지
[Clears Throat]
No, I just got up.
아니, 지금 일어났어
What, you can't access the site?
사이트 접속이 안돼?
Yeah. All right. I'll be right over.
알았어, 금방 갈게
Yes. Coffee would be good.
커피 좋지
Will it be a cup of Ethiopian coffee?
이디오피아 커피 줄 거야?
Okay.
알았어
##[Stereo: Reggae] Good morning.
좋은 아침
[Woman] Morning, Don!
Hey, you two. Keep your
eyes on the Cheerios.
뺏기기 전에 얼른 먹어
[Man] # Galloping donkey #
How's the sweetest grape
on the vine? I'm good.
예쁜 아줌마, 안녕?
안녕해요
Winston is in the back, on his computer,
그이는 사무실에서
컴퓨터하고 있어요
in his office.
Irie. [Chuckles]
아이리
Thank you, Don.
고맙습니다
[Keyboard Clacking]
What's up, Winston? Hey, Don. Listen.
I can't seem to access this site.
잘 있었어?
이거 접속이 통 안돼
I... I need your computer
expertise. Yeah? What is it?
- 전문가인 자네가 봐줘
- 무슨 사이트인데?
It's like a whole system for breaking
down the plots of detective fiction...
접속 거부
범죄수사나 추리소설
집필에 필요한 자료가
or the solution of crimes.
엄청 많은 곳이야
Y... Click.
클릭클릭...
Yes. You see?
봤지?
And click. I tried before.
해도 안돼
Stay calm. Click. Uh...
- 진정해
- 클릭, 우와
[Chuckles] Go get 'em, Sherlock.
- 됐어, 홈즈 선생
- 오, 좋아, 좋아
Cool, cool, cool.
Oh, this is my kind of information, man.
바로 이거야
I love the Net. [Laughing]
인터넷 만세
The whole world of information...
through the wall, click.
온갖 정보가
벽을 넘고 오지
You sure you don't want a
computer at your house? No.
정말 집에 컴퓨터 안 놔?
- 안 놔
- 정말 이상하다니까
Seems awful strange to me.
A man who made all of his money off of
computers doesn't want to have one in his house.
컴퓨터로 돈 번 집에
컴퓨터가 없다니
Oh!
오...
Cool. Cool. This is fascinating.
죽인다
Supposedly, you can use this
to write a mystery novel...
이걸로 추리소설도 쓰고
or to solve a complicated crime.
범죄 해결도 가능하...
If...
근데
Don.
돈!
You all right?
괜찮아?
What?
뭐?
Is something wrong?
왜 그래?
Well, it's probably nothing.
아, 별 것 아니야
Uh, a love letter from
one of your lovely ladies.
헤어진 애인한테 온
러브레터?
Something like that.
비슷해
I'll read it to you.
읽어줄게
"Dear Don, sometimes life
brings some strange surprises.
돈, 살다 보면 이상한 일로
놀라기도 해
"It's been almost 20 years
since we've seen each other,
헤어진 지 20년이 지난
"but now there's something
I need to tell you.
지금이지만 할 말이 있어
"Years ago, after our story ended,
우리가 헤어진 후
"I discovered I was pregnant.
난 임신한 걸 알았지
"I decided to go through with the
pregnancy, and I had a baby, a son.
난 낳기로 결심했고
아들을 낳았어
"Your son.
당신 아들을
"I decided to raise him by myself
because our time together...
난 나 혼자 키우기로
"had come to a close.
결심했지
"My son is now almost 19.
벌써 19살이 다 돼가
"He's somewhat shy and
secretive, unlike you,
당신과 달리
수줍음 많고 말없지만
"but a sensitive, wonderful person.
섬세하고 착한 애야
"A few days ago he left
on a mysterious road trip,
그 애가 며칠 전
말없이 여행을 떠났어
"but I'm almost certain he's
searching for his father.
아버지를 찾아간 게
확실하단 느낌이 들어
"I've told him almost nothing about you,
당신에 대해 스스로
알아본 것 같아
"but he's resourceful and imaginative.
똑똑하고 상상력이 풍부하거든
"Anyway, if this is, in
fact, your correct address,
만약 이게
맞는 주소라면
well, I just felt I
should let you know."
어쨌든 당신도
알아야 할 일이니까
There's no signature...
이름도 없고
and no return address.
주소도 없어
Hey, congratulations! You're a father.
축하해!
애 아빠가 됐어!
Uh, you're really upset by this. C
- Can I see it?
정말 화났구만
봐도 돼?
Your address is handwritten,
겉봉 주소는
육필에 정자 체
but printed.
Red ink on pink paper.
분홍 종이에
붉은 잉크
Typewriter.
타자 글씨
A red ribbon. Curious.
역시 붉은색이야
궁금해지는군
"Dear Don, sometimes"...
돈, 살다 보면...
Hmm.
흠...
Damn. This postmark is too
faint to read. That's fucked up.
소인이 끊어져서
못 읽겠어
Tsk-tsk.
쯧쯧
[Chuckles] And you have
no idea who this is from?
전혀 감이 안 잡혀?
Nope.
전혀
None.
But from all I know,
자넨 예전에
돈 주앙 같은
바람둥이였으니
you are like, uh... like Don
Juan or something. [Chuckling]
Don Juan.
돈 주앙...
[Muttering]
I gotta go.
갈래
You want me to keep the letter
for forensic evidence or... clues?
편지는 증거들로
내가 보관할까?
Or... Don.
돈!
[Sniffs]
Hmm.
##[Stereo: Woman Singing Opera]
[Doorbell Rings]
[Door Opens]
[Winston] Hey, it's me.
나야
I see that.
그러네
It's kind of lonely in here, man.
뭐가 이리 우울해?
Do you mind?
줄여도 되지?
##[Volume Down]
Is Sherry coming home? No.
- 오늘은 쉐리 없어?
- 없어
She left.
갔어
What do you mean, "She
left"? She went on a trip?
갔다니? 여행 말이야?
No. I mean, she left.
아니, 아주 갔다고
Sorry, man.
유감이네
Yeah, me too. I think.
나도 그런 것 같아
Well, but knowing Sherry, she probably
hasn't played her last card yet. Right?
쉐리 성격에 그렇게
끝은 안낼 거야
Probably not.
그럴지도
Anyway, you've never had trouble
finding interesting females.
어쨌든 자넨
여자 사귀는데 도사잖아
I mean, uh, that's the way your
life has been though. Right?
평생 그랬었지
You're like, uh... like Don Juan.
자넨 돈 주앙 같아
Winston, please stop saying that.
돈 주앙 소리 좀 그만 해
Hey.
이봐
About this letter... I did examine
the postmark under my microscope.
이 편지 말이야
현미경으로 자세히 봤는데
And it is too faint
to read, but the stamp-
소인은 너무 흐렸지만
우표엔...
it's got on it a woodpecker.
딱따구리 그림이 있었어
What does that mean to you? Anything?
뭐 생각나는 거 없어?
전혀?
Well, what I think we should do...
범위를 줄이는 게
is to narrow down the possibilities.
중요하다고 봐
Winston, this is probably
someone playing a joke on me.
단순히 장난일 수도 있어
If not, then...
아님...
whatever.
나도 몰라
It seems so unfair... someone
to write a letter like this...
이런 걸 보내면서
and-and-and
not sign it?
이름도 안 쓰다니
Don't you want to know who
is the mother of your son?
애 엄마가 누군지
안 궁금해?
My hypothetical son? No, Winston.
가상의 아들 엄마?
I don't, okay?
전혀 안 궁금해
알겠어?
Okay.
알았어
Then we can just drop it. We can?
- 손 떼지 뭐
- 정말이지?
We can, of course. Okay.
정말이지, 그럼
Good. It's dropped.
잘됐군, 손 뗀 거야
But then how can you
ignore something like this?
어떻게 이런 걸 그냥 넘어가?
- 이건 계시가 틀림없어
- 무슨 계시?
- You need to treat this as a sign.
- What kind of sign?
Of the direction of your life.
삶의 방향이라던가
Of this present moment.
현재의 삶에 대한
You need to solve this mystery...
어쨌든 자넨
수수께끼를 들고
20년 전 어떤 여자한테
and find out which of your women it was that
you impregnated with your semen 20 years ago.
씨를 뿌렸는지 알아내야 해
Winston.
제발!
What happened to that
groovin' CD I burned for you?
내가 구워준
뻑 가는 씨디는 어쨌어?
Here it is. Do you mind?
여기 있네, 튼다
## [World Beat]
Ah, that's nice. Ethiopian sounds.
죽인다, 이디오피아
음악은 말이야
It's good for the heart.
심장에 좋아
Look, come over tomorrow
for, uh, Sunday brunch,
내일 늦은 아침 먹으러
우리 집에 와
and, uh, we'll talk a little further
about our investigative plan, huh?
이 문제에 대해
좀더 얘기하자고
So I'll leave that right there.
편지 여기 둘게
Go home and leave me alone.
제발 집에 좀 가
Okay, man. I love you too.
그래, 나도 자네 사랑해
[Door Opens, Closes]
너희 아빠 정체는
콜롬보인가 봐
I think your father's
real name is Sam Spade.
My father isn't Sam Spade.
울 아빠 콜롬보 아냐
No? Think he's Sherlock Holmes?
그럼 셜록 홈즈인가?
No.
아니
Well, I know he's one of those
famous detectives. Mike Hammer!
분명 유명한 탐정인데...
포와로?
No, not Mike Hammer.
포와로 아냐
Oh, I know. He's that
Dolemite guy. Right?
알았다, 가제트다
No, not Dolemite. No?
아니, 가제트 아냐
아니야?
[Boy Shouting]
[Shouts, Laughs] He's down.
넘어졌네
Keep your eyes open.
He may be Dolemite. No!
잘 지켜봐
가제트 맞을 거야
- 아냐
- 모나
Mona,
thank you.
고마워요
That was so delicious. [Chuckles]
You're welcome. Anytime.
- 음식 정말 맛있었어
- 오면 언제든지 해줄게요
Really? Mm-hmm.
- 정말?
- 네
그럼 몇 시에
저녁 먹으러 올까?
What time's dinner?
You are the most perfect
woman in the world.
당신은 세상에서
제일 완벽한 여자야
Hey, hey, hey. Let me tell
you something. That's mine.
저리 가, 내 꺼야
Come, come, come.
저쪽으로 가지
No cigarettes. [Winston Scoffs]
담배는 안돼요!
That's where you get your appetite.
잘 먹었으니
한 대 해야겠지
Your woman cooks too good.
자네 아내
요리 솜씨가 대단해
I'd like to look at that pink
letter again. Let me see it.
그 편지 다시 줘봐
I burned it last night...
microwave. Yes, little Rita?
- 어젯밤 전자렌지로 태워버렸어
- 왜, 리타야?
Papa, you're smoking again.
또 담배 피우잖아
No, no, no. This is just herbs.
It's just a little Cheeba. Hmm?
이건 그냥
'연초'라는 놀이야
Let me see that.
어디 봐
He's right. It's just cannabis sativa.
아빠 말이 맞아
평범한 '남초'야
You see? Just a little indigo, baby.
들었지?
그냥 '담바고'란다
'Cause Mama says, "No more
smoking tobacco anymore."
담배는 안 된다고
엄마가 그랬어
Yeah, I know. I gave it up. Never!
- 알았다, 안 피울게
- 정말
Never! No more tobacco. I promise. Okay.
- 정말, 다신 안 피워
- 알았어
Come, come, come, come. Let me
see this mysterious pink letter.
그 분홍 편지 다시 줘봐
Okay. What you have to
do for me is make a list.
제일 먼저 할 건
목록 작성이야
A list.
목록
I need the possibilities
of who the mother might be.
옛 애인들 중
애 엄마일...
You give me a list of all your
girlfriends from back then,
가능성 있는 사람들을
적어서 주면
and then I can plan everything.
내가 작전을 짤게
Uh, I think I'm going home, Sherlock.
안녕히 계셔, 탐정나리
Just destroy that letter when
you're through with it, will you?
그 편지 다 읽으면 찢어버려
Work on that list.
목록이나 작성해!
##[Stereo: Ethiopian Jazz]
[Rings]
Hello, Winston?
윈스턴인가?
What list?
무슨 목록?
까맣게 잊고 있었어
No, haven't even thought about it.
Are you on a cell phone?
지금 이거 핸드폰이야?
맞아, 목록 가지러
지금 가도 되지?
Yeah. Is it okay if I
run in and grab that list?
Sure. Why not? Great. Hold on a second.
- 어서 옵쇼
- 잠깐만 기다려
Any other info on where they might be?
주소들은 알아?
Not really. That's where they
lived or their families lived.
옛날 주소랑
가족들 주소
That's all I can remember. Good. Cool.
- 그거 밖에 몰라
- 좋아, 좋아
Okay. Sorry about that. It's okay.
- 실례했네
- 천만에
Look, man. I'm all over this.
이 일에만 전념하니까
The day after tomorrow,
I'll have everything ready.
내일 모래까진 될 거야
Knock yourself out.
열심히 해보셔
[Train Whistle Blowing]
Don, man, my lunch break's
almost over. Sorry. What's up?
점심시간 다 끝났잖아!
미안, 어떻게 됐어?
Look, I got all the info
right here, based on your list,
여기 다 찾아놨고
plus the whole plan.
여행 계획까지 세워놨지
You got addresses, married names,
주소, 결혼 후의 이름
in some cases even their jobs.
그리고 직업까지
I've got some sad news though. What?
- 안 좋은 소식이 있어
- 뭔데?
That girl named Michelle Pepe?
미셸 페페라는 여자
She died in a car accident...
5년 전 차 사고로 죽었어
five years ago.
I found the name of the cemetery
where she... well, where she is.
묻힌 묘지 이름은 알아놨지만
Little Michelle Pepe?
미셸 페페가 정말?
Yeah. I'm sorry.
정말 안됐어
But the other four...
I got all their info.
다른 넷의 정보는 여기 있어
Well, that's... very
impressive, Winston.
대단하긴 한데...
I really don't know why you did all of
this. What am I supposed to do about it?
자네 왜 이래?
나보고 어쩌라고?
Look, your whole
trip... it's all planned.
여행 계획을 다 짜놨다니까
Booked reservations, rental
cars. Everything you need.
호텔에서 렌터카까지
필요한 건 다 준비됐어
- All you have to do is give them the credit card.
- What are you talking about?
신용카드만 내놔
지금 뭔 소리야?
You go visit them. You go to
their houses. You see them.
가서 만나는 거야!
직접 만나라고
You bring flowers, pink
flowers. You're just checking in.
분홍 꽃다발 들고
안부 인사차 들른 척 해
Just checking in.
안부 인사차...
여행준비 완료에
지도까지 뽑아놨어
I even got maps. Everything you need.
And I burned you a new CD, see?
새 씨디도 구워놨지
That's traveling music. That I'll take.
- 여행용 음악이야
- 이건 받을게
Uh, just coffee,
please, Avis. Thank you.
- 커피만 줘요, 아비스
- 고마워요
A few tips though. Dress
conservative, a little classy.
꼭 점잖고 품위있는
복장으로 가
Don't give anything away.
찾아간 진짜 이유는
말하지 말고
And always, always bring
flowers. Pink flowers.
분홍색 꽃다발도
절대 잊지마
And look for clues about your
son... photographs, anything.
아들 단서를 찾아봐
사진 같은 거
Or hints, like pink
stationery and red ink.
분홍 편지지나
붉은 잉크, 필적도
Handwriting, if possible.
And find that typewriter.
타자기도 찾아봐
Bring me that typewriter,
타자기를 찾으면
꼭 가져와
and then I can forensically
match the type...
법의학 기술로
비교분석 해줄게
to the letter.
[Sighs] You're insane, Winston.
미쳤구만
Even if you could possibly
rope me into this nonsense,
내 등을 떠밀어 그 짓을
which you can't,
시킨다 쳐도
I'm not a detective, I'm not a private
eye in one of your crime novels.
탐정도 아닌데
그게 말이 되냐고
Forget it. No fuckin' way.
이제 됐어, 됐다고
What, after all the work
I've done? Well, you do it.
내가 이 고생을 했는데도?
자네가 다녀와
You take the trip. I'll pay for it.
내가 돈 대줄게
Me? Impossible. I've got
three jobs and five kids.
안돼, 직장이 셋에
애가 다섯이야
And, besides, it's your life.
그리고 이건 자네 일이야
I've merely prepared the strategy.
작전은 내가 짜도
But only you can solve the mystery.
해결은 자네만 가능해
And why is that?
어째서?
Because you understand women.
자넨 여자를 잘 아니까
Let me ask you something.
뭐 하나 물어보자
Suppose I took this ridiculous trip,
만약 진짜로
그 애가 있어서
and say this kid really exists,
나 없는 새
and he shows up... while I'm gone.
찾아오면 어떻게 해?
Don, don't worry. I'll
monitor your house every day.
내가 자네 집을
매일 감시할게
Yeah? Then what? What do
you do? If he shows up?
그러셔?
그래서 만약 오면?
- 만약 오면?
- 만약 오면
He shows up. Don't
worry. I apprehend him.
체포해놓고 있지
Oh, okay. Great. You apprehend him.
그래, 실컷 체포하고 있어
Look, I've got seven minutes
before I'm due to punch in.
7분 밖에 안 남았다
Tomorrow morning, on my way to the
plant, I will drop you at the airport.
내일 출근길에
공항에 데려다 줄게
No problem. I got you an early flight.
첫 비행기로 잡아놨거든
It's not gonna happen. No way.
안 가, 절대 안 가
I'll pick you up tomorrow
morning at 7:00 a.m. Sharp.
7시 정각에 데리러 갈게
##[R&B]
#I want you # #And I want you #
# The right way I want you #
#Listen, but I want you to want me too #
# The right way, babe #
#Just like I want you #
# Ooh-hoo, ooh #
#I'll give you all the love #
#I want in return #
#Sweet darling #
#But half the love #
#Is all I feel #
#
Ooh-ooh-ooh #
#Don't play with something #
# You should cherish for life #
# Oh, baby #
#Don't you wanna care #
#Ain't it lonely out there #
#I want you #
# The right way, baby #
#I want you, babe #
#But I want you to want me too, baby #
# Got to, got to, got to #
# Want you to want me too #
#Love me too # #Baby #
# Oh, the way that I love
you # #Just like I love you ##
[Bell Chimes]
[Girl] My mom won't let me wear a bikini. [Girl #2]
I can't believe your mom let you come on this trip.
우리 엄만
비키니도 못 입게 해
여행 허락은
어떻게 받았니?
Oh, she doesn't know. I mean, she knows,
but she thinks that I'm with your family.
모르셔
너희 가족이랑
같이 간다고 했거든
No, she wouldn't have let me come, and
you would have been totally mad at me.
아님 절대 못 왔어
What if she calls my mom? She's not gonna
call her. She thinks that she's here.
전화하시면 어떡해?
전화는 절대 안 하실 거야
See, it's perfect. No, it'll be fine.
Don't worry. Wait, wait, wait. What?
- 완벽하잖아
- 걱정하지마
Don't even worry about it. Do I need to call
my mom? 'Cause my mom will totally lie for you.
- 걱정 말라니까
- 엄마한테 말해 놓을까?
I want to go to the party tonight, and I
really want to be able to meet some cute guys.
파티에서 멋진 애들을
만나고 싶어 죽겠어
That guy is so cute that's
sitting behind me. Can you see him?
내 뒤의 남자 끝장이다
보여?
- 어머, 어떡해
- 죽인다, 얘
Oh, my God. He's really cute
though. Don't stare at him.
슈퍼모델 같아
He is cute. He looks like a supermodel.
No, he looks like the Calvin Klein model that's
on the side of the bus. Oh, my gosh. He's so cool.
캘빈 클라인 모델처럼 생겼어
어머, 어머!
미모 작살이다
He's totally staring at us right now. Think Ally will
take us to get something to eat before we go? I'm starving!
난 배고파 죽겠어
That's why you need the
mix-and-match for when you get fat.
살찌면 옷 스타일이
안 살아
우린 너무 뚱뚱해
Oh, my God. I know! We're such
heifers. You get the bigger sizes.
난 살찐 것 같아
I look so fat. Doughnut girl.
도너츠 같아
[Fast Chattering]
[Bell Dinging]
[Engine Starts]
##[Ethiopian Jazz]
Look for clues,
단서를 찾는다
like a typewriter, like something pink.
타자기나...
분홍색 물건 같은...
This will be very easy.
그래, 쉬운 일이야
Hi, Laura. It's me, Don. Remember me?
안녕, 로라
나 기억해? 돈이야
[Door Bell: Muted Ringing]
Hi. Who are you?
누구세요?
Don Johnston. [Chuckles] Really?
난 돈 존스톤인데...
You're Don Johnson? Yeah... No.
- 영화 배우 돈 존슨?
- 아니
Johnston with a "T." Oh.
'T'자 붙여서 존스톤
로라 다니엘스나
로라 밀러가 여기 사니?
Uh, does Laura Daniels, who was
formerly Laura Miller, live here?
Yeah. That's my mom.
우리 엄마에요
Well, I'm a very old friend of hers,
난 엄마의 옛 친구야
and I haven't seen
her in, um, in over...
오랫동안 서로 못 봐...
우선 들어오세요
Well, come on in.
##[Stereo: Rock]
곧 오실 거니까
여기 앉아서
So, my mom'll be home from work
soon, so just sit down. Here.
Make yourself comfortable.
편히 계세요
So, my name's Lola.
내 이름은 롤라에요
Well, sometimes people call me Lo,
but my really real name is Lolita.
'로'라고도 하지만
진짜는 로리타에요
Lolita?
로리타?
Yeah. [Chuckles]
네
뭐 좀 드실래요?
아이스바도 있는데
Well, I... I don't... Do you want
something? 'Cause we've got Popsicles.
- No, thanks.
- Okay.
괜찮아
Lolita. Yeah?
- 로리타
- 네?
Do you have any
brothers or sisters? Why?
혹시 오빠나 언니 있니?
왜요?
Do you think I need some?
그런 게 필요해 보여요?
[Phone Rings] Oh, wait, that's my phone.
전화다
Just... Just stay there.
I'll be right back, okay?
여기 계세요
곧 올게요
Okay.
그러지
[Phone Rings]
#And it looks so high #
#And it looks so wasted #
#And, baby, I know why #
#Ba-ba,
ba-ba-ba #
# Take my money #
# Take my time #
# Take my sister #
#I don't mind #
#Ba-ba,
ba-ba-ba #
ba-ba-ba ##
##[Tones Chiming]
[Laughing] That's so crazy.
어이 상실이야
Really?
진짜?
[Giggling] That's so sick.
너무하다
He didn't. Wait. Hold on. My
cell phone's ringing. Hello?
걔가? 잠깐, 핸드폰 왔다
여보세요?
[Giggling] Yeah. I know.
I just talked to her.
방금 그 얘기했어
That's crazy, right?
어이없지 않니?
I know.
무슨 일이시죠?
Can I help you with something?
Donny, is that you?
정말 돈이야?
Hey, Laura.
안녕, 로라?
What are you doing here?
여긴 웬일이야?
[Chuckles]
We're having chicken for dinner.
오늘 저녁은 닭 요리야
That was quite an outfit
you weren't wearing earlier.
아까 '안' 입었던 옷
대단했었어
[Lolita Giggles]
[Laura] Well, here we are.
음식 나왔어요
Then Larry exploded in a
ball of flames at the track.
래리는 레이스 중에
붙꽃이 돼서 갔고...
That happened, and now
it's just me and Lo.
그 후에 얘랑 나만 남았지
It was even on TV.
TV에도 났었어요
정말 유감이야
I'm sorry.
Lo, your head looks
just like a pineapple.
네 머리 꼭 파인애플 같아
- Mom!
- Doesn't it?
- 엄마!
- 안 그래?
Yeah, it does look like a pineapple.
응, 딱 파인애플이야
So, what, uh...
음, 그럼...
Where do you work? Oh, Mom
has her own business. Right?
직장은 어디야?
우리 엄마는
프리랜서에요, 그치?
Yeah. Really?
그래
정말?
난 옷장정리 전문가야
I'm a professional closet organizer.
Come on. No, I organize
people's closets.
진담이야?
옷장 정리가 일이지
I even do their drawers.
서랍도 해
I label everything. I
get them all organized.
전부 이름표를 붙여
정리하는 거야
I even color coordinate them.
색깔까지 조화시켜 주지
Yeah. And they pay her
for that. It's amazing.
그걸 돈 주고 시키는
사람들도 있다니까요
- Hmm.
- Mm-hmm.
- 그렇군
- 그렇다니까
[Sighs]
Lolita, I said you... Lolita!
로리타, 너... 로리타!
I said you could have a taste.
맛만 보라고 했잖아
그만하면 됐어
Now, come on. That's enough
of that. That's not cool.
음주는 안돼
Lolita. Interesting
choice of name, Laura.
로리타라니
특이한 작명센스야
What?
왜요?
So, Donny, I heard you made it
big in business a few years ago?
그건 그렇고 몇 년 전
대박났다는 소식 들었어
무슨 사업이야?
What are you into?
It was computers. Oh, high-tech stuff.
- 컴퓨터
- 첨단기술이구나
More high tech than pencils, I guess.
아마 연필보다는
첨단기술일 걸
Mr. Fancy Pants!
대단하네
[Giggling]
Yeah, my pants are fancy. So what?
내 머리가 단단하긴 해
그게 뭐?
So I see you're having a yard sale?
아까 보니 마당에
살림 내놓고 팔던데
눈치 빠르네
Uh, you got me. It's
something we do on Saturdays.
토요일마다 하는 거에요
Yeah, Larry had all this
crap in the garage, and...
차고에 래리 물건들이
너무 많아
And then I got this neighbor
to paint a sign for us.
옆집 사람한테
팻말도 부탁했죠
It's fun. [Giggles]
아주 재미있어요
헌 타자기도 있어?
Are you gonna be selling
any old, uh, typewriters?
No.
아니
Wh... That's so 20th century.
타자기라니
완전 20세기잖아
Did you come all the way down
here to get a typewriter, Don?
여기 타자기 찾으러 온 거야?
What do you want a typewriter for?
그걸로 뭐하게?
An old friend asked me if I would
look around for a typewriter.
전에 어떤 친구가
하나 구해 달랬던 게
So... I just remembered it.
문득 생각났을 뿐이야
Well...
아...
You know, I forgot to make dessert.
후식 만드는 걸 잊었다
돈은 아이스 바 싫어해요
Oh, Don doesn't like Popsicles.
Donny.
돈
여기서 뭐해?
What are you doing here?
I was just looking for a typewriter.
타자기 찾고 있어
맞아
Oh.
그랬었지
I remember.
[Sighs]
잘 있어
[Whispers] Bye.
Hey.
이봐
Bye, Don.
잘 가, 돈
Good-bye, Laura.
잘 있어, 로라
Come back sometime.
다음에 또 와
See you, Laura.
다음에 봐
[Door Closes] [Engine Starts]
얘! 들어가 옷 입어
Lo! Go. Put some clothes on.
## [Upbeat]
## [Ethiopian Jazz]
[Knocking]
[Doorbell Rings]
- 뭘 도와드릴까요?
- 도라?
Can I help you? Dora?
그런데요
Yes.
It's me, Don.
나 돈이야
Remember me?
기억해?
Oh, Don!
어머, 돈!
What... What are you doing here?
여긴 웬일이야?
I brought these flowers.
꽃을 좀 가져왔어
So beautiful. [Inhales]
예쁘다...
Wanna come in?
들어올래?
So,
그런데
여기까지 웬일이야?
what brings you out here?
근처에 왔다가 그냥 들렀어
Well, I was kind of in the
area, so I thought I'd drop in.
그렇구나
I see.
How... How did you
track me down, exactly?
그런데 날 어떻게 찾아냈어?
Uh, on the computer.
요즘 컴퓨터는
못하는 게 없잖아
They can do anything.
집 참 좋다
Nice place you've got here.
샘플 삼아 특별히
꾸며놓은 집이야
Oh, thank you. It's a nice example.
우리 부부는
부동산 일을 하거든
My husband and I are in real estate.
We sell landscape lots...
주택분양이랑
and preconstructed designer homes.
조경한 부지매매를 해
Or do you already have this
information from your computer?
그것도 컴퓨터에 나와있어?
No.
아니
분홍색 명함이네
Your card is pink.
Yes.
응
남편 '론'이
재미있겠다고 해서
Ron, my husband, thought it would be
cute if mine were pink and his blue.
내 거는 분홍
그이 거는 파랑
그 진주 예쁜데
I like those pearls.
Did I give you those?
내가 줬던가?
I don't think so.
아닐 걸
그랬어야 했는데
I should have.
[Clock Bell Chiming]
It's very strange, your
showing up like this.
이렇게 나타나니까
정말 이상하다
Yeah, it is strange.
그래, 이상하지
[Door Opens]
It's my husband. [Door Closes]
남편이야
Hey! Where's my perfect little wi...
우리 예쁜 마나님...
Well, what have we here?
누구신가요?
Hi. Don Johnston.
돈 존스톤
도라의 오래된 친구죠
I'm a really old friend of Dora's. Oh.
You don't look really
old. Just kinda old.
그리 '오래된' 얼굴은
아니네요, 좀 삭았지만
I'm Ron.
론입니다
- 존스톤 씨라고요?
- 네
Don Johnston. Mm-hmm.
That's an old flame
of yours, right, honey?
당신 옛날 애인이신가 봐
Don just dropped in
completely unexpectedly.
전혀 예상 못했는데
들르러 왔네요
Wow! Nice to meet you, Don. [Chuckles]
만나서 반갑습니다
Ron and Don.
'론'과 '돈'
[Chuckling]
Hey, uh, is Don gonna
stay for dinner? I hope.
여보, 이 분도
저녁 같이하는 거지?
No. I really couldn't.
아뇨
그건 안될 것 같습니다
Well, sure you could.
안될 거 없잖아요
Right? Honey?
그렇지? 여보?
[Ron] Computers, huh? Wow.
컴퓨터라...
That's gotta be a lucrative field.
그거 돈 되는 장사죠
Yeah, I've done pretty well.
네, 괜찮게 벌었어요
Hmm. Well, the real estate
biz has been very good to us.
우린 부동산으로
재미를 봤어요
그렇지, 여보?
Right, hon?
At first I had the idea of
going into bottled water.
처음엔 생수 사업을
생각했었어
I think in the near future, water
will be worth more than oil or gold.
곧 물이 기름보다
금보다 더 비싸질 테니
Yeah. You're dying of thirst,
you can't take a swig of oil.
맞아, 아무리 목 말라도
기름은 못 마셔요
Right?
그렇죠?
금도 당연히 못 마시고
Or gold, for that matter. [Chuckles]
Boy, you are certainly right about that.
지당하십니다
But for right now,
하지만 지금은...
we decided that real estate
and quality prefab homes...
부동산과 주택분양에
was the right way to go.
전념할 시기예요
And it has been quite
lucrative. [Chuckles]
벌써 꽤 벌었답니다
Hon, those are beautiful flowers.
여보, 꽃이 참 예뻐
네
Mmm.
Hey! [Laughs]
맞다
Don, I want to show you
something. Excuse me.
보여줄 게 있어요
실례
[Chuckles]
근사하지 않습니까?
Isn't this the coolest photo?
Wow. Yeah.
와, 그러네요
Yeah? This is crazy, right?
정말 놀랄 노자죠
My straight little Dora.
보수파에 순진한
우리 마나님이...
My adorable little Dora. Mmm.
정말 사랑스런
우리 마나님이...
Young hippie chick. [Chuckles]
이런 히피족이었다니
That is great, Ron. Now,
could you please put it back?
여보, 이제 그만
사진 치워요
Sorry, baby.
미안해, 여보
Probably brings back one
or two memories, huh, Don?
옛 추억이 생각나지 않나요?
[Chuckles]
I took that photo, didn't I?
내가 찍은 사진이잖아
[Laughs]
Mm-hmm.
맞아요
[Sighs]
Well, you know, it's strange...
세월 따라 사람도
how people's lives change, isn't it?
변한다고... 그렇죠?
[Ron Chuckles]
So, any kids?
자녀는 있나요?
Well, that's... that's
kind of a touchy subject.
그건 좀 거북한 주제군요
See, I always wanted
to have kids with Dora.
나는 애들을 갖고 싶었지만
You know, I mean, kids of our own.
도라와 저의 아이들이요
But she didn't, really,
so I respect that.
도라는 반대했고
난 그 의견을 존중해요
Oh, I don't know if I would have had the
time and patience to be a good mother...
난 참을성도
시간도 부족해서
론의 애들에게
좋은 엄마가 못됐을걸요
to... to Ron's children.
I'm just happy to have my Dora.
도라만 있으면
난 행복합니다
What about you, Don?
존스톤 씨는요?
You married?
결혼했나요?
No, I'm still a bachelor.
아직 독신입니다
A bachelor?
독신?
Wow.
와...
But any kids? He said
he was still a bachelor.
애들은?
아직 독신이라잖아요
[Laughs] Well, honey, you know...
그래도 모르잖아
You never know. One or
two could have gotten away.
한 둘 있었을지
[Chuckling]
내가 아는 한
애는 없어요
No. No kids I know of.
[Chuckling Continues]
[Rings]
Hello, Winston.
안녕, 윈스턴?
[Winston Speaking, Faint,
Unintelligible] Just a crazy guess.
맞춰봐
이게 뭔 짓인진 몰라도
Look, I don't know
what I'm doing up here.
전혀 진전이 없어
I'm gettin' nowhere.
응, 만났어
Yeah, I saw her.
Yeah, I saw her too.
그 쪽도 만났고
Yesterday.
어제
No. No clues.
아무 단서도
타자기도 전혀 없어
No typewriters.
Couldn't you have rented me, like, a Porsche
or some car that I might really drive?
그런데, 포르쉐라도
준비하면 어디 덧나나?
I'm a stalker in a Taurus.
이건 완전
서민형 스토커잖아
[Winston Continues,
Faint, Unintelligible]
I have done everything that
you wanted me to do, you know.
자네 하라는 대로
다 했고...
정말 할 만큼 했어
I... I... I've really
had enough of this.
I think I oughta go back today.
오늘 돌아갈 거야
Yeah, but I... I don't... I
don't think I wanna see her.
아, 만나기 싫어
No, Winston...
나중에 얘기하자
알았지?
Winston, let me... let me
talk to you later, okay?
저기, 제발...
나중에 얘기하자, 응?
저기 있잖아
Can I just... Yeah.
Let me talk to you later. Please?
나중에 얘기하자, 제발
Okay? Thanks. [Winston Continues
Chattering, Unintelligible]
알았지? 고마워
[Whinnying]
I'll talk to you in a while. Okay?
다음에 얘기하자
[Bell Dinging]
곧 목적지에 도착하오니
[Flight Attendant On P.A.] Ladies and
gentlemen, we're now on our final descent.
자리로 돌아가
Please return to your seats and make sure your
seat belts are securely fastened. Thank you.
안전벨트를 착용해 주십시오
감사합니다
## [Car Stereo: Jazz]
## [Continues]
[Car Door Opens]
[Engine Off] ##[Stops]
[Whispering] I heard what you said.
And I heard what Dr. Markowski said.
You have to believe in yourself.
I have a lot of respect for you.
I understand how you feel.
네 기분 알아
이제 더 노력할게
I understand, and I'll
try to do better next time.
Hi.
안녕하세요
그 말을 꺼낸 용기가 장하다
It takes a lot of courage to say
what you said. I'm very proud of you.
네가 자랑스러워
이제까지 아주 잘했어
And I want you to know that I think
you're doing very, very well...
난 널 믿는다
and I believe in you.
Yeah, she definitely speaks to iguanas.
물론 이구아나도
소통 가능합니다
Okay. That's right.
네, 그럼요
월요일에 다시 전화 주시면
시간 잡아놓겠습니다
Call back on Monday and we'll
happily schedule you and Iggy.
Sure. Mm-kay. Thank you.
그럼요, 감사합니다
I'm sorry, Mr. Johnston, but Dr.
Markowski only takes appointments,
죄송하지만 박사님은
예약상담만 하십니다
and she's in a session right now.
지금도 상담 중이시고요
Is your animal friend with you?
동물도 같이 왔나요?
Uh, no, I... I... I don't
have an animal friend.
그게 아니라
칼멘... 박사의 오랜 친굽니다
I'm an old friend of
Carm... uh, Dr. Markowski's.
Um, Carmen has a really tight schedule.
일정이 차서
시간이 날지 모르겠어요
She may have a minute,
if you want to sit down.
기다려보세요
Yeah, okay.
네, 좋아요
No, no, no. Of course I
won't forget you, Cleo.
그렇지 않아, 클레오
널 잊지 않을 거야
Yes, I promise.
약속해
Thank you, Dr. Markowski. Mm-hmm.
고마워요, 박사님
잘 있어요
- Bye now.
- Bye, Cleo.
안녕, 클레오
See you next week, Mrs. Dorston.
안녕히 가세요, 부인
[Door Closes] [Footsteps]
So, what do we have next?
다음은 누구지?
[Exhales] Don? [Chuckles]
돈?
So, you're an animal psychic?
동물 마음을
읽게 된 거야?
No. I'm a communicator.
아니, 나는
동물 의사 소통사야
And you're a doctor now? Mmm.
박사가 된 거야?
예전엔 변호사 되려고
열심이였잖아
When we were together, you were so
passionate about becoming a lawyer.
I mean, you were...
그때 당신은
정말 열정을 쏟았었는데
very passionate.
열정이란 묘한 거지
Yeah, well, passion's a funny thing.
대신 난
동물 행동학 박사가 됐어
I have a doctorate in animal behavior.
But that was sort of after the fact.
기묘한 그 일이 있은
It's an odd story.
후의 일이야
I'm getting into odd stories.
요즘 묘한 얘기
많이 듣네
[Sighs] Well, I was a
very successful lawyer.
잘 나가는 변호사였는데
I had no life, though, outside my work,
내 개 윈스턴이
유일한 낙이었어
except for my dog, Winston.
Your dog's named Winston?
개 이름이 윈스턴?
그래
Yes.
그런데 그 개가 죽었어
But then he died...
suddenly.
정말 갑자기
- 미안
- 아냐
I'm sorry. Oh, no. It was, uh...
벌써 옛날 일인걸
It was years ago.
But my new ability was this gift.
나의 새 능력은 선물이었어
윈스턴의 선물이었어
This gift from Winston.
All right, you can come in again.
그래, 들어오렴
Anyway,
어쨌든...
after Winston died I got this gift.
윈스턴이 죽은 후
능력이 생겼고
To-
음
- 동물의 마음을 읽는 능력?
- 아니, 아까 말했잖아
To read animals'
minds? No. I told you...
- No.
- I'm a communicator.
난 의사 소통사라고
You see, soon after Winston died...
윈스턴이 죽은 직후
동물들의 말이
들리기 시작했어
I realized that I could
hear animals speak to me.
I mean, I certainly hadn't
been aware of that before.
전엔 그런 적이 없었는데
마음을 읽는 게 아니야
And I don't read animals' minds.
But when they want to communicate,
동물이 말하는 걸
들을 수 있는 거지
I can hear them.
우리도 말을 하는 거지
You know, like you and I are talking.
But we don't read each other's minds.
마음을 읽는 건 아니잖아
그 녀석이 뭐라고 해?
Is he saying something?
He says you have a hidden agenda.
당신이 뭔가
숨기고 있다는데
He... He said that?
정말 그랬어?
이제 다시
나가보는 게 좋겠다, 라몬
I think you'd better go
back outside now, Ramon.
Animals can tell us what they want,
동물들이 원하는 것이
꼭 그애들에게
다 이로운 것 만은 아니야
but that doesn't mean that
that's what's best for them.
[Knocking] [Carmen] Yes?
네?
Excuse me, Carmen, but Mr. Renaldo and
Skippy are here for your next session.
레날도 씨와
스키피가 기다립니다
아, 그래
Oh. Okay.
1분만 있다가 갈게
Um, give me one more minute.
Sorry, Don, but I really
can't keep Skippy waiting.
미안, 스키피를
기다리게 할 수 없어
Do you think you could tell Skippy that
you're just gonna walk me to my car?
차까지 배웅할 동안만
기다리면 안될까?
How about later? Wanna get a drink?
이따가 한 잔 할래?
난 술 안 마셔
No. I don't drink.
Maybe get something to eat?
그럼 밥이라도?
안 먹어
밥...
I don't, uh, eat.
밥을 안 먹어?
You don't?
그럼 산책할까?
Uh, take a walk?
- 걷긴 하잖아
- 그럴 기분이 아니야
I know you walk. I don't feel like it.
혹시 타자기 있어?
Do you have a typewriter?
A typewriter?
타자기?
결혼은 했고?
Are you married?
You know, I think you
should probably go now.
이제 그만 가
그러지 말고, 칼멘
Oh, come on, Carmen.
Can't you answer me? No.
- 대답해줘
- 아니
"No," you won't answer me?
대답 안 할 거야?
[Laughs] No, I'm not married.
아니, 결혼 안 했다고
한 적은 있었지만
I was though.
Any kids?
애는?
Yes.
있어
I have a daughter, Lianna. She's 16.
16살짜리 딸, 리아나야
[Sighs]
She's in Sweden.
스웨덴에 있지
Sweden.
스웨덴?
Am I supposed to ask about you?
내가 물을 차례인가?
나에 대해
다 말했으니...
It seems like I've told
you my whole life story.
나?
So
- Me? No.
I'm not married.
난 결혼 안했어
Of course you aren't.
물론 그렇겠지
And I don't have any kids.
애도 없고...
Do I?
없는 거겠지?
How would I know that?
내가 그걸 어떻게 알아?
레날도 씨랑 스키피가
기다려요, 칼멘
Sorry, Carmen, but Mr. Renaldo and Skippy
have been waiting in the session room.
I know. I'm sorry. I'll be right there.
미안해, 금방 갈게
Okay.
이제 정말 가야 돼
Well, my time is really up.
So, good-bye.
안녕
Bye, Carmen.
안녕, 칼멘
[Door Closes]
Mr. Johnston? You forgot your flowers.
꽃을 놓고 가셨네요
존스톤 씨
[Door Closes]
[Phone Rings]
[Rings]
잠깐만! 잠깐만요!
Hey. Excuse me! Excuse me.
Excuse me. Uh, do you
know where Atwood Road is?
앳우드 길이 어딥니까?
## [Metal] I'm lost.
길을 잃었어요
[Emergency Brake Sets]
[Engine Off]
[Door Alarm Dinging]
[Dog Barks] Oh!
엇...
Hey. [Barking Continues]
이봐...
Hey, it's okay.
진정해
진정하라고
It's okay.
##[Metal] Can I help you?
무슨 일이슈?
Does Penny live here?
여기 페니가 사나요?
Who's askin'?
댁은 뉘슈?
옛날 친구인
돈 존스톤입니다
I'm an old friend of
Penny's. Don. Don Johnston.
She's in the house. Go
around there. A screen door.
집 안에 있수다
뒷편 방충망을 두드리슈
Thanks.
고맙습니다
##[Continues]
[Knocking]
Penny?
페니?
Hello?
누구세요?
- 페니?
- 그런데요?
- Penny?
- Yeah?
돈...
Donny.
이건 뭐 하는 수작이지?
So, what the fuck do you want, Donny?
Oh, I just thought I'd drop by.
그냥 들렀어
Just checking in.
안부인사나 하려고
Well, I don't remember any
happy ending between us, Don.
그리 좋게 끝난 사이가
아니었을 텐데
화해한 기억도 없고
No... reconciliation, nothing.
You left me, Penny. Remember?
떠난 건 당신이야
기억 안 나?
Yeah.
그럼
똑똑히 기억하지
Very clearly.
대체 왜 온 건데?
So, what is it you wanted?
무슨 일 있어?
Everything okay over there, Pen?
아직은 몰라!
Not sure yet!
Goddamn it.
젠장
What is it you wanted?
그래서 뭐?
페니, 당신...
Penny, do you...
혹시 아들이 있어?
Do you have a son?
Fuck you, Donny!
꺼져, 개자식아!
Danny, grab that fucker.
대니, 이 자식 꽉 잡아
Penny!
페니!
[Sighs] Shut up.
닥쳐
아무 말도 안 했는데요
I didn't say anything.
[Footsteps]
What the hell's your fuckin'
problem? I was just leaving.
너 뭐 하는 새끼야?
지금 돌아갈 겁니다
페니를 왜 저렇게
화나게 했어?
No, what are you doing upsetting Penny like
that, huh? I just needed to ask her a question.
뭐 하나 물어본 것 뿐입니다
그건 나도 알아
그런데...
Yeah, I know you asked her
a question. Now, listen.
I just don't think it's
very sensitive of you...
찾아와서까지
저렇게 상처 주는 게
훌륭한 짓이란
생각은 안 들어
comin' out here to try
to hurt Penny's feelings,
you know, to get back
at her or whatever.
이유야 뭐던 간에
무례하단 말이야!
That just seems so rude.
[Fumbling With Door Handle]
[Door Opens]
[Engine Starts]
[Warning Bell Dinging]
[Dinging Stops]
[Groans Softly]
전부 분홍이죠?
You said all pink, right?
분홍만으로 해줘요
[Don] It's best that
they're all pink, yeah.
Oh, you're very good at this.
솜씨가 아주 좋네요
- 예쁘군요
- 고맙습니다
That's beautiful. Thanks.
Are you okay?
다치셨어요?
Uh, it was just a
minor misunderstanding.
오해가 좀 있어서
Mind if I take a look?
한 번 봐도 돼요?
Oh. That's nasty.
우와, 심하다
Did you even wash it?
소독은 하셨어요?
Sort of.
대충
제가 해드릴게요
Let me take care of it.
이름이 뭐에요?
What's your name?
썬, 썬 그린이요
Sun. Sun Green.
썬 그린?
Sun Green?
Perfect.
근사한데
손님은요?
What's yours?
돈, 돈 존스톤
Don. Don Johnston.
[Giggles] Really?
정말요?
Don Johnson? Johnston.
- 영화배우 돈 존슨?
- 존스톤
'T'자 붙여서
With a "T."
그럼...
So...
이 길을 쭉 가면
if I continue down this road,
I will find the Riverview Cemetery?
묘지가 있다는 거죠?
Yeah. You just go down the hill.
You'll see the entrance on your right.
언덕 아래 오른쪽에
입구가 보여요
고마워요, 썬 그린
Thank you, Sun Green.
You're welcome.
별말씀을요
[Bells Jingling]
Hello, beautiful.
안녕, 예쁜 아가씨...
Red ink on pink paper.
분홍 종이에
붉은 잉크...
##[Rock]
내가 뭘 원하는지
나도 몰라
I don't know what I want.
당신이 뭔가
숨기고 있다는데
[Carmen] He says you
have a hidden agenda.
꺼져, 개자식아!
Fuck you, Donny.
서클 드라이브
천천히 가요
Circle Drive, please. No rush.
[TV Clicks On]
## [Jazz]
The wheel of fortune turns.
Round and round it goes.
돌아라, 돌아
운명의 바퀴야
어디 설지 아무도 모르지
Where it stops, no one knows.
##[Continues]
Boy.
아들이다
[TV Clicks Off]
그게 다야
홈즈 선생
That's my report, Sherlock.
자네 때문에 겪은
쌩 쇼의 요약버전
The general outline of
what you put me through.
이게 다야?
That's it?
그 난리를 겪고도
And after all that, you're still no closer
to knowing who's the mother of your son?
애 엄마를 못 찾았다고?
That's right.
그래
타자기랑
But there was that one typewriter.
분홍 오토바이가 있었다며
And the pink motorcycle.
도라의 분홍 명함과
And it was Dora's
pink, uh, business card.
로라의 분홍 가운도
And-And-And Laura's
pink bathrobe.
마치 한 편의 실패한
광대극을 본 듯해
I think this whole thing
is a farce, a fiasco.
As far as I know,
그 편지
you may have written that letter to me.
자네 장난일 수도 있었다고
자네 눈이
밤탱이가 된 건 유감이야
Look, I'm really sorry that
you got beat up and everything.
아마 내 책임도
약간 있을지도...
I... I... I... I feel that
it was somehow my fault.
자네 책임 맞거든
It was.
신기했던 건
Kind of strange, too, how, uh,
칼멘의 요술 강아지도
'윈스턴'이었지
Carmen's magic dog was named Winston.
흠...
Yeah... [Stammers]
Look, man, I really put a
lot of work into this thing.
난 최선을 다해 도운 거야
아들이 정말 있는지를
I thought that it was really important
that you know whether or not you had a son.
아는 건 중요해
자네 인생을
되찾아야 하잖아
I mean, it's your life. You
got to live your life, right?
I was living my life, Winston.
난 인생을
잃은 적이 없거든
지금도 그렇고
I still am.
What's this? It's pink.
그게 뭐야?
분홍색이네
돌아오니까
거실에 있었어
It's a note I found in
my foyer when I got back.
Red ink on pink paper.
분홍 종이에 붉은 잉크
It's from Sherry.
쉐리 편지야
What? From Sherry?
쉐리 편지?
Why didn't you tell me? May I see it?
왜 말 안했어?
어디 봐
Envelope and paper not
exactly the same size.
봉투랑 종이...
크기는 전과 다르네
필적은...
You know, the handwriting...
전의 것과 거의 흡사해
확신은 못해도
seems pretty close to the address
on the envelope, but I can't be sure.
Sherry still likes you.
아직도 자넬 좋아하는군
You think that Sherry could
have sent the first letter...
혹시... 쉐리가 자넬
엿 먹이려고
and made the whole thing
up just to fuck with you?
꾸민 짓이라 생각해?
Who knows?
누가 알아?
You know, I've got to go.
이제 가야겠어
I think I have just enough time to
stop home and compare the handwriting...
집에 잠깐 들러
필적 비교해도
제 시간에 타임카드
찍을 수 있을 거야
and then hopefully
punch in at work on time.
- 자네도 갈래?
- 아니
You coming? No.
다 잊고 좀 쉬고 싶어
I just need a little
break from all of this.
Look, don't worry.
걱정 마
We're still going to solve this mystery.
우리가 꼭 알아낼 테니
[Engine Starts]
Didn't I see you at
the airport last night?
우리, 어제 공항에서
보지 않았나?
글쎄요, 봤나?
I don't know. Did you?
Yeah.
봤어
지금 배낭 여행 중?
You on a road trip?
비슷해요
Yeah. Something like that.
배고파 보이는데
샌드위치라도 사줄까?
You look hungry. Can I buy
you a sandwich or something?
괜찮아요
Uh, no, that's okay.
걱정 마
게이도 경찰도 아니니까
You can relax. I'm
not gay. I'm not a cop.
배고파 보이는 사람을
바라보는 사람이지
Just a guy who sees a guy
who might need a sandwich.
좋아요, 그럼
Okay. Thanks.
포장해 올 수 있어요?
밖이 편해서...
But could you get something to
go? I'd sorta rather stay outside.
Sure.
그러지
클럽 샌드위치 괜찮아?
How about a nice club sandwich?
난 채식주의예요
I'm vegetarian.
치즈는 먹어?
You eat cheese?
먹어요
치즈 좋아해요
Yeah, sometimes. I... I like cheese.
알았어, 금방 올게
Okay, I got it. I'll be right back.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Thanks. You're welcome.
Hey.
어이
자리 잘 잡았군
You found us a place.
좋아
All right.
어디 보자
Let's see here.
치즈랑 버섯이 든
Big cheese and veggie sandwich...
야채 샌드위치 큰 거
with mushrooms.
Fries... Mmm.
특대 사이즈
감자튀김
Extra large.
물 두 병
Two waters.
Two coffees.
커피 둘
엄마가 부적으로
My mom put that there...
for good luck.
달아놨어요
Thanks for the food.
음식 고마워요
천만에, 보스
Ahh. No problem, chief.
날 보스라 불렀어요?
You called me chief?
그래, 왜?
Yeah. Why?
What happened to your eye?
눈은 왜 그래요?
음...
I, uh...
누구랑 부딪혔어
I ran into somebody.
누구 주먹이랑
Somebody's fist.
아저씨, 조폭?
You a gangster?
아니, 그럼 좋겠지만
No. I wish.
No, I was, uh... I was in computers.
난 컴퓨터에 빠졌었지
컴퓨터랑 여자에
Computers and girls.
보스는?
What about you, chief?
I'm interested in, uh, philosophy.
난 철학이 좋아요
철학이랑 여자
Philosophy and girls.
그거 근사한 걸
Sounds pretty good.
Think so?
그래요?
음...
So, uh,
배고픈 자에게
밥을 준 사람으로서
as just a guy who gave
another guy a sandwich,
배낭여행자한테 말해줄
you have any, like,
philosophical tips or anything...
인생철학 있어요?
for a guy on a kind of road trip?
You asking me?
나한테 하는 말?
네
Yeah.
어디 보자
Well...
과거는 지나갔지
The past is gone.
당연한 거지
I know that.
그리고 미래는
The future...
isn't here yet,
아직 오지 않았지
뭐가 어떻게 될지
아무도 몰라
whatever it's going to be.
그러니
So,
여기 있는 건...
있는 건...
all there is is... is this.
현재야
The present.
이게 다야
That's it.
불교신자에요?
Are you a Buddhist?
아니, 너는?
No. Are you?
아직 몰라요
Uh, I'm not sure yet.
그게 해줄 수 있는 전부야
미안하다
I'm sorry that's the best I
have to offer at the moment.
아녜요, 고마워요
No, I appreciate it.
마음에 들어요
I like what you said.
아빠처럼 훈계 늘어놓는
It's better than some, like,
그것보단 훨씬 낫네
fatherly-sounding bullshit.
그래...
Is that...
너희 아버지가 그러시니?
what your father's like?
곤란한 주제네
Ah, that's not a good subject.
- 이제 갈래요
- 미안하다
Hey, I gotta go, man. I'm sorry.
샌드위치 고마웠어요
Thanks again for the sandwich and stuff.
Hold on a second. Wait.
잠깐! 잠깐만!
내가 네 아버지라고
생각하는 거 다 알아
I know you think that I'm
your father, don't you?
뭐요?
What? Just tell me. You
can talk to me, chief.
솔직히 말해봐, 보스
Man, you're fucked up.
이거 미친 놈 아냐?
잠깐! 잠깐! 잠깐만!
Wait a second. Wait a second. Wait!